Smith College.
Smith College Archives
Alumnae Oral History Project
2010-2013
Smith College.
RG12
11 boxes (4.6 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
The Smith College Alumnae Oral History Project collection is comprised of oral histories conducted with alumnae during Reunion weekends in 2010, 2011, 2012 and 2013. The collection contains video recordings, transcripts, and project records.
Historical Note
The Smith College Alumnae Oral History Project was funded by the President's Office and the College Archives and coordinated by Kelly Anderson. Students from the Archives Concentration and Anderson's class in oral history conducted the interviews with alumnae over Reunion weekend in May 2010, 2011, 2012 and 2013 in the Alumnae Gymnasium. Interviews were 30 minutes long, on average, and were taped by videographer Kate Geis and Rebecca Rideout, as well as student interviewers. Narrators were asked to reflect on their reasons for choosing Smith, key experiences during their time on campus, significant political and social issues that marked their time at Smith and the impact a Smith education has had on their lives and careers. In 2010, narrators graduated from the classes of 1985-2005. In 2011, narrators were graduates of the classes of 1941-1976. In 2012, narrators were mostly graduates of the classes 1957-1982. In 2013, narrators were primarily graduates of the classes 1943-2008.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The collection contains video recordings, transcripts, and project records.
2010: Narrators and class year
Evans, Katharine, 2000: In this oral history, Katharine Evans discusses her decision to attend Smith, her experiences playing sports (field hockey, lacrosse, and squash) and living in Lamont House, and her study of biology (major) and chemistry (minor). She also describes her life after Smith-working at a nonprofit, attending graduate school, and her current career as a physical therapist.
Fang, Clara, 2005: In this oral history, Clara Fang discusses her involvement with MassPIRG, working to oppose drilling in the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge, interning at the Environmental Science and Policy Program, working with the student group Gaia, and starting a student organization called Clean Energy for Smith. Fang also talks about living in Park House, going abroad at Oxford University, her experiences as an English major, racial tensions on campus, the impact of the September 11th attacks on Smith, and her life after Smith, attending the University of Utah and Yale, and working as an environmental professional.
Hall, Ginna Rohan, 1985: In this oral history, Ginna Rohan Hall discusses growing up in Northampton and how that impacted her time at Smith, her experiences living in Baldwin, Northrop, and Morris, and her work as a psychology major. She also describes issues of diversity at Smith, and the impact that Smith has had on her life.
Homestead, Melissa, 1985: In this oral history, Melissa Homestead discusses living in Lawrence House, Wilder House, and Parsons Annex, her experiences as an English major and her thesis on Willa Cather, and her participation in music clubs and the Lesbian Alliance. Homestead also describes issues surrounding sexuality and lesbianism, the Hover House controversy, incidents of homophobia and tensions between heterosexual and homosexual students, the Feminist and Lesbian Alumnae of Smith College (FLASC) group, and her experiences at the University of Pennsylvania.
Joslyn, Erin, 1990: In this oral history, Erin Joslyn discusses her involvement with the student publication The Green Age, her experiences living in Hopkins, studying in Cambridge, England, and her work as an art history major. Josyln also describes the overall campus atmosphere, including issues of diversity and tensions between heterosexual and homosexual students. Finally, Joslyn talks about the societal difficulties and pressures that women face, what it feels like to be back at her Smith reunion, and who she has become since Smith - working as an art historian, owning an antiques business, and working as a writer on several different projects.
Kahler, Jean, 2000: In this oral history, Jean Kahler discusses her decision to come to Smith, her experiences living in Hubbard House, her work as a theater major, her process of coming out as a lesbian, and the overall atmosphere surrounding homosexuality.
McCarthy, Katie, 2005: In this oral history, Katie McCarthy discusses her work as a psychology and education double major, and her involvement with SGA and Senate, Healthy Heads (a mental health support group), and Residence Life. She also describes the racial tensions on campus and her experiences while abroad in Australia.
Merrill, Christine, 2005: In this oral history, Christine Merrill discusses her experiences on the crew team and the swim team, her time abroad in Geneva, Switzerland and travels in Europe, and her work as an art history major.
Miller, Mariceleste, 1990: In this oral history, Mariceleste Miller discusses her experiences living in Morris House and Park House, her involvement with theater, and her work as a biology major and math minor. She also describes the general campus climate and atmosphere (including racial tensions), Helen Caldicott's commencement address, and her current work with the Smith admissions office in Baltimore, Maryland.
Moe, Nina, 2001: In this oral history, Nina Moe describes her experience coming to Smith from Europe (Norway and Poland), her coming out process, her work in the music department at Smith, and her current career as a musician. She also describes the campus atmosphere, including racial tensions and issues around sexual and gender diversity.
Perkins, KP, 1985: In this oral history, KP Perkins discusses why she decided to attend Smith, her involvement in extracurricular activities (including student activism), and her work as an Afro-American studies and French double major. She also describes the general campus atmosphere, particularly in regards to race, and her opinion of President Conway.
Pic, Sara, 2000: In this oral history, Sara Pic describes her involvement with activism at Smith (including her association with the Lesbian Avengers and working for transgender student rights), living in Hubbard House, her experiences abroad in Russia, her work as a Russian Civilization major and with the Study of the Women and Gender, and her decision to go to Northeastern Law School.
Revuluri, Sindhu, 2000: In this oral history, Sindhu Revuluri discusses her decision to attend Smith, her experiences living in King House, her participation in the Student Government Association and music clubs, her coming out experience, and her summer abroad in Ghana. She also describes the general campus atmosphere and incidents concerning conservative Smith students, and her graduate school experiences at Princeton University.
Rosen, Melanie, 2000: In this oral history, Melanie Rosen discusses her decision to attend Smith, her experiences living in Wilson House, working as a Gold Key guide, participating on the crew team, her work as a French studies major and Afro-American studies minor, and her time abroad in Paris and West Africa. She also describes the overall campus atmosphere and her experiences as a Fulbright scholar after Smith.
Rowe, Jess, 1997: In this oral history, Jess Rowe explains her decision to come to Smith, her work as a Painting and English double major, her coming out process and relationship with her partner, and her experiences after leaving Smith.
Skinner, Brittain, 2000: In this oral history, Brittain Skinner describes why she came to Smith, her experiences studying at the University of Kentucky for two semesters and how it compared to Smith, her work as an English major and biology minor, her experiences living in Wilson House and her role as house president, and her involvement with the Helen Hills Hills Chapel Protestant group. She also explains what it has meant to her to be a Smith graduate.
Tierney, Meghan, 2000: In this oral history, Meghan Tierney discusses her experiences living in Lamont House, playing on the volleyball and softball teams, acting as the Vice President of her class, and working in the Alumnae House. She also describes her time at the Smithsonian program, her work as an art history and archaeology minor, and her life after Smith.
Tolentino, Ana, 1985: In this oral history, Ana Tolentino discusses how she decided to attend Smith, her departure from Smith to attend the University of Wisconsin in Madison for a semester, and her return to Smith. Tolentino also describes her time at Smith, including her experiences as an art history major and archaeology minor, and the atmosphere of the early 1980s.
Trabucchi, Sarah, 2000: In this oral history, Sarah Trabucchi discusses her experiences living in Lamont House, participating in the theater department and working with the Northampton High School theater program, and her work as an American Studies major. She also describes the 1996 Presidential election, gay rights, and the general campus atmosphere.
Wallace, Sophia, 2000: In this oral history, Sophia Wallace discusses her involvement with WOZQ radio, FIRE (Feminist Intercultural Revolutionary Encounter), PULSE (an art collective), rugby, and various activist activities. She also describes her appreciation of President Simmons, her experiences in Sessions House, her time studying abroad in Ghana, and the general atmosphere of Smith, particularly in regards to diversity.
Werner, Mary 1985: In this oral history, Mary Werner explains why she chose to attend Smith, her experiences with Student Senate, tutoring local children, and her work as a psychology major. She also describes the general campus atmosphere and diversity, her opinions on President Conway, and her life after Smith.
2011: Narrators and class year
Ames, Judith Silverman, 1961: In this oral history, Judith Silverman Ames discusses why she chose to attend Smith, her experiences living in Clark House, her participation playing on various sports teams and with musical groups. Ames also describes the campus atmosphere, the lack of diversity, the benefits of same-sex education, her post-Smith experiences living abroad in Mexico and Japan, and her various career choices.
Baldonado, Sandra, 1956: In this oral history, Sandy Baldonado describes the overall campus atmosphere, her experiences living in Hubbard House, participating in sports and theater, designing her own international relations major, her work at the CIA, and what a Smith education has meant to her.
Baydin, Adele, 1951: In this oral history, Adele Baydin discusses her experiences living in Chapin House, what it was like being a Jewish student at Smith, her travels in Europe, and why she decided to leave Smith after her sophomore year.
Bennett, Elaine, 1981: In this oral history, Elaine Bennett discusses her initial reactions to Smith, her experiences living in Ziskind House, her work as a theater major. Bennett also describes the dialogues surrounding feminism during the late 1970s and early 80s, the lesbian community on campus, and what it feels like returning to campus for reunion.
Bickerton, Marianne 1976: In this oral history, Mary Bickerton discusses her involvement in choir and service organizations, the campus dialogues surrounding feminism, and issues of race and class, and what a Smith education has meant to her.
Brush, Sally Anderson, 1956: In this oral history, Sally Anderson Brush describes the campus atmosphere of Smith during the early 1950s, the lack of diversity and issues of race, and the expectation that one would marry. Brush also discusses her involvement with the crew team, the Christian Association, Judicial Board, her experiences as a religion major, her interactions with Gloria Steinem, and how Smith has impacted her life.
Carr, Carolyn, 1961: In this oral history, Carolyn Carr discusses her work within the Art department (including spending a summer studying art in Italy), how it affected her later career, her experiences taking a class with Sylvia Plath, and her transition to Smith from a small town in Virginia. Carr also describes issues of race and the Civil Rights Movement on campus, and her reaction to the Newton Arvin pornography scandal.
Christensen, Ann, 1956: In this oral history, Ann Christensen discusses how Smith shaped her as a person, what it was like adjusting to Smith coming from the South, issues of race and diversity, her experiences living in Haven House, and who she has become since attending Smith.
Denison, Judith Snow, 1957: In this oral history, Judy Denison describes her experiences living in Lawrence House as a scholarship student, her work as a physics major, her internship at the CERN, and her education after Smith. Denison also discusses her marriage and subsequent divorce, her children and grandchildren, and her job with the Bureau of the Census and recent work with the Belize Education Project.
DeSanti, Carole, 1981: In this oral history, Carole DeSanti describes why she decided to attend Smith and what it was like to adjust to the new atmosphere, her work as an English major, and her Marxist feminist philosophy. DeSanti also discusses the Lesbian Alliance and issues of sexuality, Hover House, reactions to the national press coverage of Smith in the early 1980s, and her opinion of President Conway.
Esty, Katherine, 1956: In this oral history, Katharine Esty describes the political and social atmosphere at Smith during the McCarthy era, her experiences living in Jordan House and the divide between Jewish and non-Jewish students within the house, student protests regarding the Hungarian Revolution, the dating scene and how she met her husband at Amherst College, the lack of racial diversity within the student body, the impact that Betty Friedan's book The Feminine Mystique had on her, and her later work for UNICEF and as a psychotherapist.
Gesing, Susan, 1961: In this oral history, Susan Gesing describes what it was like arriving at Smith from the Midwest, what the dating scene and social atmosphere were like, her work as an American Studies major, her opinion on the Newton Arvin scandal, and what a Smith education has meant to her.
Grace, Martha, 1961: In this oral history, Martha Grace discusses the overall atmosphere at Smith, her work as a zoology major, her experiences living in Dewey House, her marriage after her junior year, what a Smith education has meant to her, and her decision to attend law school and obtain a Masters degree in Animals and Public Policy.
Group interview, Class of 1946, Margaret Craig DeMott; Jane Hill; Rosalie Taylor Howlett; Helen Goddard; Abby Minot Gross: In this oral history, Abby Minot Gross, Rosalie Taylor Howlett, Jane Hill, Helen Goddard, Margaret DeMott, and Araxi Prevot discuss what it was like being at Smith during World War II, working on the farms, the fire in Dickinson House, and what it has meant to them to be Smith graduates.
Hazeltine, Glenna, 1966: In this oral history, Glenna Hazeltine describes why she chose to attend Smith, her reactions upon arrival, the overall campus atmosphere, her membership with the SDS, her involvement with Gold Key and The Sophian, her work as an English major, her opinion of President Mendenhall, and what a Smith education has meant to her.
Heller, Deborah, 1961: In this oral history, Deborah Heller discusses adjusting to Smith from Brooklyn, issues of diversity, the social pressures and her life after Smith, including her marriage, divorce, and coming out process, her involvement within the LGBT community, and her current work to establish an LGBTQQ alum affinity group.
Imbrie, Charity, 1976: In this oral history, Charity Imbrie describes her initial reaction to Smith, her involvement with choir and her work within the music department, the political and social atmosphere at Smith (particularly in regards to feminism and lesbianism), and her work within the legal field.
Johns, Yvonne, 1961: In this oral history, Yvonne Johns describes the overall campus atmosphere, the dating scene, her experiences as president of Gillett House, her work as an American Studies major, her experiences as a woman working within the Civil Rights movement, and what a Smith education has meant to her.
King, Sheryl, 1971: In this oral history, Sheryl King discusses what it was like being Southern at Smith during the late 1960s/early 70s, the overall campus atmosphere (particularly in regards to activism and feminism), and her experiences after Smith.
Klein, Phyllis (Patti), 1961: In this oral history, Phyllis "Patti" Klein describes the overall campus atmosphere, her work in the history, art history, and English departments, and her life after Smith.
Martin, Marilyn Johnson, 1957: In this oral history, Marilyn Johnston Martin discusses living in Lawrence House, her social life, her relationship with Sylvia Plath, issues of class, her decision to leave after her sophomore year, and her life after Smith.
McClure, Karen Lewis, 1961: In this oral history, Karen McClure describes the overall campus atmosphere, her involvement in sports, her work as a sociology major, issues of diversity, the dating scene, her experiences living in Wesley House, and what it feels like to be back at Smith.
Mooney, Jean Bradley, 1956: In this oral history, Jean Mooney discusses her work as an Education major, issues of diversity and class on campus, and her career in education.
Nelson, Marilyn Carlson, 1961: In this oral history, Marilyn Carlson Nelson describes why she decided to attend Smith, her experiences studying abroad in Geneva, her work within the theater and dance departments, her experiences working in the business world and as CEO of the Nelson Group, one of the largest privately held companies in the world, and what a Smith education has meant to her.
Pires-Hester, Laura, 1961: In this oral history, Laura Pires-Hester describes how she decided to attend Smith, what the overall campus atmosphere was like, her experiences living in Albright House, issues of race and class, the beginning of the Civil Rights Movement, her work to increase the racial diversity on campus, her life and work after Smith, and what a Smith education has meant to her.
Prevot, Araxi, 1946: In this oral history, Araxi Prevot discusses being at Smith during World War II, working on the community farms, her experiences living in Cushing House and the French House, attending a summer session at Smith, her life after Smith, and what a Smith education has meant to her.
Siderowf, Topsy, 1961: In this oral history, Topsy Siderowf discusses the overall campus atmosphere, her work as a history major, the dating scene, the beginning of the Civil Rights Movement, her interactions with Sylvia Plath, and her work at Golf Digest.
Spencer, Joyce, 1961: In this oral history, Joyce Spencer describes the overall campus atmosphere, her experiences singing in the choir, issues of race, ethnicity, and religion, and her life after Smith.
Taylor, Nell Cochrane, 1951: In this oral history, Nell Cochrane Taylor discusses her experiences living in Lawrence House, her various roles of leadership on campus, issues of race and class, campus reactions to the Vietnam War, her position on the Board of Counselors and Board of Trustees, her experience receiving the John M. Greene award, her work with the Committee on African-American Studies, and her life after Smith.
Thoresen, Susan Warner, 1966: In this oral history, Sue Thoresen describes why she chose to attend Smith, the overall campus atmosphere, her experiences singing in the choir and glee club, the social changes that occurred at Smith during her time there, campus reactions to the Vietnam War, and her life after Smith.
Walker, Janet Smith, 1961: In this oral history, Janet Walker discusses what a Smith education has meant to her, her work as a history major, her experiences living in Gardiner House, issues of diversity, and describes a typical Smith student during the late 1950s.
Wang, Kathleen (Kit), 1981: In this oral history, Kit Wang describes the overall campus atmosphere (especially in regards to lesbianism, homophobia, and race), her experiences living in Hubbard House and Hover House, her work as a biochemistry major, her participation in the first national gay rights march on Washington, her involvement with the Lesbian Alliance, her experiences in seminary, and current work as an Episcopal priest.
Woods, Eleanor C., 1961: In this oral history, Eleanor Woods describes her experiences playing in the orchestra, her continuing involvement with music, the dating scene at Smith, issues of racial diversity, the alumnae reaction to the Newton Arvin controversy, and what a Smith education has meant to her.
2012: Narrators and class year
Bershadsky, Edith, 1977: In this oral history, Edith Bershadsky describes her experiences living in Sessions House, specifically her experience dining with the male exchange students, the tradition of tea, being a feminist, and the strong friendships she formed at Smith.
Blankevoort, Eefje, AMS 2004: In this oral history Eefje Blankevoort compares the education system at Smith with her experiences in the Netherlands, discusses the new perspectives she received at Smith, her experiences in Iran before coming to Smith, and her surprise that the Iraq War was so ignored in the United States.
Boylan, Roberta Walsh, 1962: In this oral history, Roberta Walsh Boylan describes coming to Smith from Montana, living in Gillett house, campaigning for laxer social rules, moving to San Francisco after graduation with Mary Ann Savage Habib, going to Law School, and being the first woman at University of Montana Law School.
Cooper, Ruth, 1957: In this oral history, Ruth Cooper describes going to Smith in the mid-1950s and the social regulations that entailed, working hard academically, traditions like Ivy Day and after dinner coffee, and how Smith had changed when her daughter attended in the 1980s.
Cunningham, Patricia, 1947: In this oral history, Patricia Cunningham describes living in Comstock, studying abroad in Mexico, focusing on her studies rather than on dating, feeling as though women should be able to do anything and being gratified when feminism began developing a few years after she graduated from Smith. Lastly, she describes working in France and her experiences in the Foreign Service. RESTRICTED TO THE SMITH COMMUNITY
Davis, Nancy, 1982: In this oral history, Nancy Davis describes falling in love with Smith and the importance of house community to her experience. She talks about racial dynamics on campus, her participation in the Bridge program, student activism, feminism, the changes she has seen at Smith, and her experience as a class officer for her reunion.
Deutsch, Jo, 1982: In this oral history Jo Deutsch discusses her house community in Baldwin House, the Northampton feminist and lesbian communities, President Conway, and her first relationship with a woman at the end of her senior year. She touches upon her work as a lobbyist for 27 years and her current position at Freedom to Marry.
Devaney, Anne, 1977: In this oral history, Anne Devaney describes being at Smith for its' Centennial, living in Wilder, Washburn, and Lawrence and the house traditions she remembers, the struggle for funding for the lesbian organization Sophia's Sisters, being the only white student in an African American literature class, the excitement and happiness around President Conway's appointment, her experiences as head of rec council, and her career after Smith in student services and human resources.